Thomas Miller

Frontend Web Developer

thomas.miller147@gmail.com

0 1630 Bulle, Switzerland

github.com/Meuss





+41 79 560 20 71

01.09.1987



Swiss nationality

thomasmiller.ch



Internet enthousiast, I have been building websites since 2013. Bilingual French-English and self-taught mostly thanks to online tutorials, I am constantly improving my knowledge and I fully commit to my projects, looking to be proud of what I build. My goal is to continue gain more expertise in the frontend world by working on interesting projects, both visually and functionality-wise.

Education

2010 - 2014

Bachelor of Arts in Information Systems

University of Fribourg

2003 - 2008

Maturité fédérale

Collège du Sud, Bulle

Language skills

Bilingual French/English

German: good knowledge Spanish: basic knowledge

Online resources

Podcast fanatic Courses such as frontendmasters, Wes Bos, Level Up Tuts, Udemy and many others.

Professional experience

Sept - Nov 2019

Frontend dev / WordPress @ CDI digital, Fribourg

I worked together with .NET developers on the frontend side of projects: WordPress, legacy projects Sitefinity/Telerik and a Vue.js project.

2015 - 2019

Web dev @ macmac SA, Marly

I learned a lot about how to build websites, from start to finish. Our projects were mainly websites built around a CMS or small SPAs with JS frameworks (Vue, Nuxt). I was the only developer on most of the projects: using the given designs, I was responsible to choose the tech stacks and build the websites based on the client's needs. I learned how to create interesting responsive layouts, animations and interactivity, all while keeping an eye on performance, crossbrowser issues and SEO. I also built a couple eCommerce websites with WooCommerce and Shopify.

2016 - Today

Freelancing

I've been freelancing a bit for small projects for a couple years now.

Coding













Javascript (ES6+) HTML / CSS PHP SASS CSS / SVG animations Crossbrowser Responsive web design

Tools









Vue.js

Nuxt.js jQuery

npm Babel

Greensock Webpack Gulp

WordPress Kirbv Prismic Woocommerce Shopify

CMS

🕠 🙍 🚾 🐧

Design





Sketch Photoshop Webflow